<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quality of Data | Luca Di Gennaro Splendore, Phd</title>
    <link>https://lucadgsplendore.netlify.app/tag/quality-of-data/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lucadgsplendore.netlify.app/tag/quality-of-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Quality of Data</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://lucadgsplendore.netlify.app/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Quality of Data</title>
      <link>https://lucadgsplendore.netlify.app/tag/quality-of-data/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19: Unprecedented Situation, Unprecedented Official Data, Unprecedented Quality Data</title>
      <link>https://lucadgsplendore.netlify.app/publication/covid-19-unprecedented-situation-un-precedented-official-data-unprecedented-quality-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lucadgsplendore.netlify.app/publication/covid-19-unprecedented-situation-un-precedented-official-data-unprecedented-quality-data/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/514290913&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random testing, quality of data and lack of information: COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://lucadgsplendore.netlify.app/publication/random-testing-quality-of-data-and-lack-of-information-covid-19-data-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lucadgsplendore.netlify.app/publication/random-testing-quality-of-data-and-lack-of-information-covid-19-data-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;quality-of-data&#34;&gt;Quality of Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t do any blood tests then you don’t have high cholesterol. The cases of COVID-19 depend on how many persons each country tested and how they were tested. For instance availability of the test, asymptomatic cases, whether only the people in the hospital are tested, or whether only the people in contact with infected people are tested, random test… The number of cases of COVID-19 is not a trustable measure of how many people are infected by COVIS-19. Moreover, it is useless for comparison. Infection by the virus can be provisionally diagnosed on the basis of symptoms, though confirmation is ultimately by an appropriate test. In most countries, the COVID-19 test policy changed over time. More probable than not we cannot compare over time the data of the same country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of cases of COVID-19 is essential to calculate the Case Fatality Rate (CFR). The “mortality rate” is different from the CFR¹. I read quite a lot of confusing thoughts in the media. The CFR is the proportion of deaths from a certain disease compared to the total number of people diagnosed with the disease: deaths by COVID-19 of the total diagnosed cases of COVID-19. Whereas, the mortality rate is a measure of the number of deaths in a particular population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there an overestimation of the CFR of COVID-19? Probably yes, if we calculate the CFR of COVID-19: death from COVID-19 to cases of infection of COVID-19. And if you underestimate the cases of infection of COVID-19, your case fatality rate (CFR) is higher. The cases of the infected are at the lower bound of the real situation. Seeing that we have not tested all of the population, in this case, this figure can be greatly biased downwards due to the non scientific sampling of the number of infections of COVID-19. The cases of COVID-19 should be tested by conducting a scientific random sample.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-need-proper-information&#34;&gt;We need proper information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cases of COVID-19 should be tested by conducting a scientific random sample. Thanks to the scientific sample we can have all the information to fully understand the situation. For instance, if we want to analyse the Spanish or Maltaese situation, then the random sampling should be extracted from the entire Spanish or Maltese population. We can randomly select approximately 1000 people from amongst the Spanish people. Then every person in the sample will be tested (COVID-19 swab) but then they will also receive a questionnaire. The questionnaire will be focused on social habits, such as travelling, going to restaurants, family meetings, pubs, discos and whether they had contact with people with the COVID-19 virus. Like that we can have a picture of the phenomena and understand how many people have asymptomatic COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-sample-covid19-representative-of-the-population&#34;&gt;A sample COVID19 representative of the population&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the entire population, a random sample representative of the population can be extracted. Every person in the sample will be tested for the COVID-19 (swab) and probably also his/her relatives. A questionnaire should accompany this random COVID-19 test survey. Questions on personal health conditions, social connections, traveling and social habits in the last weeks could be asked to the people. Probably this exercise could be repeated periodically until a stable situation is obtained or reached. A random stratified sample with an error margin of 2% at 95% confidence is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;in-conclusion&#34;&gt;In conclusion:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without data on the COVID-19 we cannot possibly understand how the pandemic is progressing locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without data we cannot respond appropriately to the threat; neither as individuals nor as a society. Nor can we learn where countermeasures against the pandemic are working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infection Fatality Rate (IFR) does not equal CFR. To calculate IFR you need to know the number of infected in the total population. IFR of COVID-19 is estimated to be 0.3–1%. In both measures, IFR and CFR, the important question is: How many people are infected? IFR will likely underestimate infection and if only those with more severe symptoms are screened, CFR will likely overestimate the fatality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
